[Music]
the stoa
is a digital campfire where we cohere in
dialogue
about what matters most at the knife's
edge of what's happening now
[Music]
boom all right everyone welcome to the
stoa
i'm peter limberg the steward of the
stoa nestoa
is a place for us to come here and
dialogue about what matters most at the
nice edge
of this very moment and today we have
adam ray
atkins from the podcast and youtube
channel the acid
left his
co-host uh mike uh watson was uh
who's the author of i think the left um
can mean
uh from zerobooks was supposed to be
here as well but he couldn't make it so
it's uh
adam is going to be here and give us a
presentation uh so
how i first came across the this acid
left thing a german jeremy johnson who's
a friend of the stoi was talking uh
about them and i just reached out on the
whim because i thought they were like
this emerging memetic tribe in the in
the noah sphere
uh and they might be and so i'm really
looking forward for this talk and
engaging in what the acid left is
talking about mark fisher and his idea
of
acid communism capitalist realism and
all that good stuff
so how today is going to work adam is
going to
uh give a presentation um and he's also
going to share a music video
uh and it might be a little trippy so
warning um if strobes and stuff like
that are not your thing
uh and after that we're gonna have a q a
so any time when adam is talking uh just
put your questions
in the chat box i will call on you to
unmute yourself to ask a question to
adam
uh if you want me to read on your behalf
because this will go on youtube
eventually
just indicate that and i will do so uh
so i think
that is everything so adam uh welcome to
the store
and uh i will take you in
[Music]
oh you're a mute you just gotta meet
yourself
ah thank you thank you peter it's nice
to be here
um yeah so i'll be doing this today
normally
with mike watson he wrote can the left
learn to meme
um and also conceptual militancy both
out on zero books
um and then we've been doing this
podcast for
a few months though we've been working
together for a little over a year
um under a couple different names and
just under our own projects um
i am a visual artist primarily i do a
lot of mixed media painting
that has incorporated politics and
philosophy
and then i do some like sound
manipulation and stuff like that
i wanted to start by reading a poem
uh so this is a poem i wrote
that's called 10 000 years in the life
of a shelf-stable reverse osmosis pulsar
if i lived 27 378 years
i would lose 1 billion hairs 99
of billionaires are not billed one
quarter of prescriptions are
not filled mixing damiana and valerian
rather than being
night quilled keep it raw keep it raw
keep it raw
not grilled want to have a voice and
then a language
get quilled want to stay living on the
bay coast
get gilled super massive black hole
truth floats around us guess he is super
massive
black hole utopia arises out of sinking
paradises super massive
black hole truth comes down on us
distilled
consciousness begins to condensate
distilled consciousness as a liquid
state
distilled flow over the cup flow
over the vase distilled flowing from a
distant place
contemplate existence as a liquid state
coming from a different space
contemplate the complexities of the
gaseous mass and the societal structures
of bacteria living in intestinal tracts
saw the future saw the future saw the
future not thrilled
these bastards are actors not masters
their labor is stolen and
unskilled don't celebrate at the
ceremony
the value and debt are both phony leave
your loans
unpaid perceptions unfilled
99 of billionaires are not billed
i saw the future saw the future saw the
future
not thrilled knock it down knock it down
knock it down
rebuild
uh all right thank you uh so
i wanted to read a poem and then i want
to
show this music video at the end because
a lot of what we're
really trying to emphasize is
alternative forms of
knowledge outside of what might be
classified as like
dry academic forms of understanding
now we are heavily influenced
around the ideas of mark fisher and
acid communism so to get into that real
fast
we have to understand what capitalist
realism is capitalist realism is a
concept
fischer coined that kind of sums up
the quote from frederick jameson that it
is easier to imagine the end of the
world
than it is the end of capitalism so this
is the idea that our imagination
has really stopped producing the novel
uh that it reproduces
uh either an apocalyptic scenario or
capitalism kind of going on forever and
ever
even in um a lot of science fiction
the future presented still remains
largely
capitalist um you can see this in
margaret thatcher's statement such as
like there is no alternative
uh and then fisher also pointed to
the assassination and coup against
salvador allende in chile um
as a major starting point like the nail
in the coffin
that that creates capitalist realism
because it offered an
alternative both to western capitalism
as well as soviet-style authoritarianism
which is an important part of the
project
that runs throughout fisher from
capitalist realism
through all of his writings is a
rejection
of the more authoritarian elements that
were associated
with communism through the you know
actually existing socialism as it's been
known to call
so then acid communism fischer late in
his life
he was working on the book acid
communism right before his death
and he the the intro to this
was published in the repeater collection
k-punk which is mostly
his old blogs some interviews
uh and some music writing so and then
also contains the
unfinished introduction to acid
communism which he sums up
kind of as the convergence of class
consciousness
socialist feminist consciousness raising
and psychedelic consciousness
the fusion of new social movements with
the communist project
an unprecedented ascetician of everyday
life
so kind of looking back and
seeing how the in the 60s and 70s
the counterculture movements never quite
were fully taken serious by the
left and vice versa so a wish for those
to come back together
uh because in those movements
the important thing is the psychedelic
as a space
and as a way of perceiving reality the
psychedelic
deals with both space and time it's a
folding of the outside in
and the inside out it's about the
erasure of
boundaries of the self in the world of
the mind and the body
and importantly it does not only do with
drugs
you know we could also point to things
like meditation art
or especially music as it is kind of
more of a temporal art form than say a
painting or something like that it
forces you
to engage with time in a specific way
uh so we find that it's important to
deal with the psychedelic
um to engage the imagination to
re-engage the imagination which has been
crushed
by capitalism um and also to save the
psychedelic
from being colonized by capitalism uh
because this is a very possible
threat that we see to this um and
the various ways we could that you could
have the psychedelic itself
be colonized um i think there's obvious
historical examples here such as
the original counterculture movements
you know like the hippies and stuff
actually became much more conservative
over time
you have big capitalist figures such as
such as steve jobs or like
the people that created whole foods you
know actually saying that
psychedelics in their past were very
important for them and kind of like
put them where they are now you see this
today
in workplace mindfulness practices
um you know large fortune 500 companies
that also have their workers
engage in yoga breaks
or tech startups in silicon valley where
almost everyone is micro dosing lsd
or psilocybin mushrooms they've kind of
taken the radical dimension
that the psychedelic movements
originally had in them
and repurposed them or stripped them of
that element
i also believe that in the psychedelic
communities existing today
there is a strong right-wing element now
of course not everyone
in there is right wing and i don't think
it in
uh uh leans this way naturally i'm not
sure it leans the psychedelic leans left
or right naturally
you do have a uh a thought that the le
that left leaning stuff is naturally
psychedelic or that
the psychedelic is naturally
left-leaning with its
questions of authority and kind of
erasures of boundary that we already
touched on
um but it's not true um you know
spiritualism psychedelia transcendent
states
all have of course reactionary elements
within them
uh today we can see this in the
psychedelic community through like
organic unity or the return to nature
this kind of position of a lost man that
needs to
connect back to something that was great
um i would fundamentally reject this
you see the ideas of levels of
enlightenment
that end up actually justifying
injustice
in the world so you know this idea that
through some kind of psychic
vibration or something that you're
actually inviting
suffering onto you so that when people
experience poverty they experience loss
it's seen as
something to do with their spiritual
state
and then also the ideas that are
prominent in the
in the psychedelic communities of shadow
forces
which also which often leads to
conspiracy uh thinking
so the shadow forces obviously would be
um on the sides where you look at
psychedelic
ideas of the illuminati
or uh dark wizards
evil magic stuff like that um and then
leaning into
reptilian control theories uh which have
their structural similarity
to anti-semitic theories running
throughout history sometimes being
almost
word for word so that's you know that's
why i'm talking about
acid communism and some elements of
psychedelia
why the acid left um well we are
inspired by fischer pretty heavily
that's what brought
mike and myself together along with
terry tapp having these conversations
but we're not only inspired by mark
fisher
uh you know our goal is not to be
a channel that specifically tries to
explain and explore fisher only you know
mike and i both have our own influences
uh that go beyond fisher and would have
our own critiques of fisher in various
portions so we didn't want to just say
oh
we are create content under the name of
acid communism you know we're not saying
we are
acid communism we're creating content
that we think
is inspired by these ideas that there's
a lot of questions
fisher's work leaves and you know we're
just trying to
take up some of those questions and ask
some more of our own
um left because we i mean essentially we
are leftists and you know
but we're also trying to build that
broader association there
that maybe the word communism in its uh
forthrightness can off can off-put
people though i
myself would consider myself a communist
um
so what we basically do is we produce
lots of memes
which have a psychedelic aesthetic um or
some kind of boundary pushing or
boundary uh eliminating purpose we
have created music in the past and
visuals to go along with the music we do
a podcast
which interviews various people working
either in
some kind of left academia left
journalism
psychedelic writing or artist
and we've also been doing the beyond
linguistics reading group
and in that we read theory or philosophy
and then we interpret it as visual arts
memes or um some kind of music or poem
so in that you know we're like actually
transforming actively the theory that
we're going through
and trying to understand it in a
different way
for someone who may not actually go
through and read those
dense texts sometimes um so that's my
my little presentation and i do want to
play a song
uh we're gonna play a music video for it
this is called a serious
joke it samples heavily from
mark fisher's acid communist
introduction
so you know here we're really we just
tried to make it fun make it something
that would be enjoyable to listen to
but also produces certain like sensory
feelings in the individual that's
engaging it i do want to stress again
it uses heavy flashing
strobe psychedelic color changes so if
you are sensitive to that
i would um probably not watch the video
uh so let me pull this up
oh i'll also say that
this video was made the xero books
channel actually hosted it for us
and it was made around the corbyn
election so there is a
a brief little corbin plug at the
beginning uh
let me oh i didn't
sorry about this y'all i have to
i have to turn my screen save sharing on
this is not something i do often if you
can't tell
um we love
technical issues here at the stoats
opportunity for us to practice our
stoicism so
no rush you do have you do have co-host
access
so you should have screen share i do
i just clicked out of it for a moment
screen
there we go um but let me make sure
all right i got audio register to vote
and vote labor does that come through
the audio
yep all right society
cut the working hours increase the
number of jobs
increase the amount of the salary
transform production and place it under
workers control
liberation of the huge amount of
intelligence that is wasted by
capitalism
technology has been used so far as a
means of control
and exploitation it wants to be turned
into a tool for liberation
working less is possible thanks to the
application of cybernetics and
informatics
zero work for income automate all
productions
all power to living labor all work to
dead labor
of course we now know that the
revolution did not happen
but the material conditions for such a
revolution are more in place in the 21st
century than they were in 1977
what has shifted beyond all recognition
since then is the existential and
emotional atmosphere
populations are resigned to the sadness
of work even as they are told that
automation is making their jobs
disappear
we must regain the optimism of that 70s
moment just as we must carefully analyze
all the machineries that capital
deployed to convert confidence into
dejection
understanding how this process of
consciousness deflation work is the
first step to reversing it
what is the bad news we already know is
that the time the dimension of the
future has disappeared
and that in some ways that when maroon
were trapped
in the 20th century still
that what is it to be in the 21st
century
is to have 21 20th century culture on
higher definition screens
or you know 20th century culture
distributed by high-speed internet
so there's a strange i mean what ought
to be a strange sense of repetition
of a clotted or blocked time
uh a timeless in many respects slowed
down or flattened or [ __ ]
you can look back at
[Music]
by the urgencies of capitalism now
now we carry them we carry them around
at all times with us
and that's important to remember you
know
describes communications communication
is a command this is one
when we open up we look at our
smartphone
essentially and this
is a
[Music]
as practically everyone says
let's reply to this question that your
student movement
was defeated that it doesn't exist
it has changed its form it still and
have actually penetrated
the
[Music]
awareness that one does not have
to work eight hours a day closing hours
required for transportation and if
without giving up most of the
achievements of culture and so on
this is one of the achievements of the
years
it feels like an actual social space one
you can imagine really existing
you are as likely to come upon a friend
or a hubster as a poet or musician here
and who knows if today's prank might
turn out to be tomorrow's genius
it is also an egalitarian and democratic
space
and a certain effect resides over
everything
there is multiplicity but little sign of
resentment or malice
it is a space for fellowship for reading
and talking as much for having your mind
feeling
the crucial defining feature of the
psychedelic is the question of
consciousness
and its relationship to what is
experienced as reality
if the very fundamentals of our
experience such as our sense of space
and time
can be altered does that not mean that
the categories by which we live
are plastic mutable yet the claims that
altered states of consciousness took you
a million miles away from reality was
question making
it foreclosed the idea that altered
state of consciousness could offer a
perception of the systems of power
exploitation and ritual that was more
not less
loose than ordinary consciousness in the
60s
when consciousness was increasingly
besieged by the fantasies and images of
advertising
and capitalist spectacles how solid was
the reality from which psychedelic
states fled in any case
wasn't the state of consciousness
susceptible to spectacle more like some
ambulance than alertness or awareness in
retrospect
one of the most remarkable features of
the psychedelic culture of the 1960s was
the way of mainstream such metaphysical
questions
experiments with consciousness were now
in principle open to anyone
despite all the mysticism and
pseudo-spiritualism which has always
hung over psychedelic culture
there was actually a demystificatory and
materialist dimension to this
widespread experiments with
consciousness promised nothing less than
a democratization of neurology itself a
newly widespread awareness of the
brain's role in producing what was
experienced
as reality those on acid trips were
externally single workings of their own
brain
and potentially learning to use their
brains differently
yet psychedelic experiences were not
confined to those who had taken drugs
rather than invoking an actually
existing past and comparing it with the
present i think it's
i think the the point of a week from
which we can criticize
the current moment the point at which it
can be found wanting
is by the it is in terms of the futures
that were projected from the 20th
century not the actual existing
past but it's the shocking difference
between what we thought might have
happened
on one level the 60s revolt was an
impressive illustration
of lenin's remark that the capitalists
will sell you the rope to play him with
in the uk stuart paul felt similar
frustrations with much of the existing
left frustrations that were all the more
intense in his case
because he thought of himself as a
socialist
but the socialism that paul wanted is
socialism that could engage with the
yearnings
and dreamings that he heard in miles
davis music
was yet to be created and its arrival
was obstructed as much by figures from
the left as from the right
the first obstructive figure of the left
was the complacent steward of called
more
organized labor or social democracy
backward looking bureaucratic resigned
to the inevitability of
capitalism more interested in preserving
the income
and status of white men than in
expanding the struggle to include
this figure is defined by compromise and
eventual failure
the other figure what i want to call the
harsh leninist superego
is defined by its absolute refusal of a
compromise
according to troy the superego is
characterized by the quantitatively
and qualitatively excessive nature of
its demands
whatever we do it's never enough
the harsh land of superego mandates the
militant diseases
the militants will be single-mindedly
dedicated to the revolutionary event
and unflinchingly committed to the means
necessary to bring it about
the harsh leninist superego is as
indifferent as suffering as it is
possible to pleasure lenin's phobic
response to music
is instructed here i can't listen to
music too often
it affects your nerves makes you want to
say stupid nice things and stroke the
heads of people who could create such
beauty while living in this pile of
health
while the complacent leaders of
organized labor were invested in the
status quo
the harsh leninist superheroes takes
everything on the world absolutely
different to this one
it was this most revolutionary world
which was redeemed
and it was from the perspective of this
world that they judged themselves
in the meantime it is legitimate and
indeed necessary to cultivate an
indifference towards current suffering
we can and must step over homeless
people because giving to charity
only obstructs the coming of the
revolution
but this revolution had little in common
with the social and psychic revolution
of almost
inconceivable magnitude that ellen
willis thought was seated in the counter
culture's dreamings
the revolution as she conceived of it
would at once
fundamentally concerned how care and
domestic arrangements were organized and
more far-reaching
the transformed world would be
unimaginably stranger than anything
marxist feminism had projected
a counter-exorcism of the specter of a
world which could be free
acid communism is the name i have given
to this specter
the concept of acid communism is a
provocation and a promise
it is a joke of sorts but one with very
serious purpose it points to something
that
at one point seemed inevitable but which
now appears impossible
the convergence of class consciousness
socialist feminist consciousness raising
and psychedelic consciousness
the fusion of new social movements with
a communist project
an unprecedented aestheticization of
everyday life
all right all right
and uh that's that's that i hope that
sounded okay over there
um and yeah i'm ready if
peter or if anyone else has any
questions
yeah um we might need a collective
moment
uh it was pretty trippy yeah good
um so yeah if anyone has questions start
throwing them in the chat
um yeah i'll start off with
one uh to warm you up uh
i'm curious how much the
alt-right reactionary type tribes that
you know angela nagle talks about kill
normies and other uh
spots in the zero books ecology talk
about uh
influence that this kind of your acid
left
um in their guerrilla warfare approach
with me
magic and stuff like that and i recall
you guys talking about edge lords in one
of your
recent interviews yeah um
well i think it's definitely played a
large part of it um
so what wilhelm reich
uh who's kind of a fringe figure from
the
german socialist movement who got into
some really weird stuff but
he had this like little idea that
basically
the right the right wing was winning
back then because
it was kind of tapping into people's
libidinal energies
and allowing them to express that in
some kind of way
while the left was you know quoting the
gdp
of india to them um and once infinitely
more more appealing to a young
person or a dispossessed person you know
and alt-right kind of seized upon that
as well by
taking some of those transgressive
politics and
we want to yeah definitely reclaim some
of those transgressive politics
for the left um and
really engage in yeah memetic warfare
absolutely uh i i i'm not i wouldn't shy
away from
that term by any means
uh and the other question i had like i
really like this approach
by the way um i sort of like through the
back door
combating the or breaking the
intersubjective and epistemic prisons we
have so we can imagine
new things um and uh
the the the thing i'm curious about is
given my meta proclivities
like i have the capacity to be friends
with all sorts of memetic tribes
um and i just used to for example have
friends people who vote for trump
friends people who are very progressive
quote unquote woke
um and you know just day-to-day
gatherings to great people
i can feel their heart but then there's
people on i would say
a lot of different memetic tribes or
different ideologies that are just
sociopaths
you know they can't feel the heart um
and so i wonder what your thought is
on but like beyond the you know getting
people out of uh you know their
cognitive prisons
um about heart based practices related
to politics
right um uh i tend to be
in favor of them you know i think
actually that's one of the things that
fisher is talking about consciousness
raising
um to bring that into the fold uh
i'm not super familiar with the term
heart based practices if it has like
really specific connotations
but what i think you're getting at i
absolutely agree and you know
i yeah i in my day-to-day life you know
i'm
not an academic i'm a working-class
person i work at a grocery store
i make art i go to coffee shops um when
there's not lockdowns
and i interact with people like that all
the time you know i live in
the south and i lived in the bible belt
of america for a long time tennessee
and yeah i know lots of right-wing
people
um in my family all throughout and you
have to talk to them
of course there does come points where
it seems impossible or
unproductive um and i would say that to
the same thing for
for a right winger you know they they
have to talk to someone on the
left wing really if they're gonna
maintain some kind of sanity and today
and i honestly believe a lot of the
that stuff really does come from traumas
from personal
and social trauma so i guess we would
really emphasize
social trauma um but
addressing personal trauma is absolutely
important as well
um and building those bridges between
people on an actual human level
is i mean if you can't do that
then you're really missing something
important that could lead to any kind of
social revolution yeah
yeah we have a upcoming event called the
the trauma scene here about like uh like
you know this is the epoch we're in
right now
uh contending with all this collective
trauma
okay so let's pivot we got some great
questions in the chat uh
andy you have a question
hi um i'm wondering individually uh
rather than
interpersonally um i look at the concept
of hauntology
as being able to view the space
of something new and the only way you
can do that
is by trying to eliminate your kind of
unconscious biases
of let's say a capitalist framework of
how things exist
exist now to how they could exist that
kind of a second order
merging between whatever cop
communism capitalism socialism something
beyond
and so the question is what are the
skills
that we can use to minimize this
unconscious capitalist cultural
framework to think
ontologically
that's uh that's a great question now i
do have to say
i'm not super familiar i know a little
bit of fisher's work on hantology
but i think i can answer this as well
but maybe not quite um
in the ontological realm um
so i think a lot of those are listening
to people sharing stories
and really trying to understand between
well i get i guess this would be
intra-personal though um
trying to understand other people and
expand yourself through them
um to know their stories to know their
consciousness
um beyond that
i'm not sure uh how it really goes you
know i think
often when people have these experiences
the the a psychedelic experience that
kind of switches you to a different
reality tunnel like that it happens in a
way that's
hard to quantify afterwards um you can't
really say
what what made you have that epiphany
in those moments
so i'm not sure how to individually
cultivate that we i mean we look at
the you know the kind of forces and
pressures that are upon us and kind of
interpolate from there
i guess you could say trying to think
about
fischer talks about the uh trying to
think about not what we are to
capitalism
but what capitalism is to us like for
the
the worker or the everyday person and
you know thinking of it in ways of it
what it has to obscure what it has to
make sure
doesn't happen is collective joy
um you know so if we think of it in
that way and looking at what stops
collective joy
what stops collective flourishing
amongst yourself
and amongst people um and then tracing
so that's really getting into like the
social traumas
i would suppose and then also trying to
connect those social traumas
with your own personal trauma so
connecting your
and then vice versa your personal
traumas when dealing with them seeing
how they connect
to larger social traumas but i guess you
have to
already have that idea or framework in
there
um somewhat
andy any follow-up
no that's helpful um
i just defer to somebody else all right
uh evan you're up
hey so i really appreciated uh what
you've been uh saying and i really like
this
aesthetic um so i guess i have a
question that i struggle with a lot
myself wanting to get your take on this
which is sort of the relationship
between um you know more modern and
and present uh expressions of of
communism
uh the tension between that and the
effectiveness of markets
so where i'm going with this is that
markets seem to be
uh obviously superior mechanisms of
resource allocation
to the sort of top-down command
economies
which were attempted to be implemented
by the uh
you know communist states of the past
and yet
unfettered market capitalism obviously
has all these terrible effects so i
think that we are
you know the the communist uh analysis
is correct and that we should be
really really focused on the sort of
distribution of
the uh of profit between say capital and
labor we should be emphasizing the
importance of labor and this sort of
conversation a lot more and so i'm
totally with the communist program in
that sense
but i also wonder what you think the
relationship is like maybe maybe
just kind of riff on like how do we take
the sort of optimization power
of the idea of a of a competitive market
and how do we you know um bind that so
that it is uh working in the service of
human flourishing human happiness
equality
all that good stuff like like how do we
sort of confront that reality of the
21st century where we have such a
complicated world um and we need things
like markets to
optimize our resource chains um and yet
uh
markets uh unfettered are so destructive
uh so just yeah if you could riff on
that for a bit
yeah um so let's see
i think you know i think like the us the
austrian school kind of has this way of
viewing the market as like a computer or
something like that
um that does all those calculations
and yes compared to
the you know like the soviet uh
economy it may be more
it has something that the soviet economy
doesn't have
absolutely or like or any of the other
ones but
i don't know if i would necessarily call
it more efficient
um i do think a big
portion of that maybe techno technology
itself
um so during those that time really the
biggest problem i think they faced
was information they didn't have
all of the information that they truly
needed if you wanted to
make a planned uh economy like that
and part of that was because of their
strict political
um uh uh repression right so like
if if a farmer thinks that he might be
shot if he says the wrong thing
uh he's gonna give the answer like to
how much he can do how much he's
produced he's gonna give whatever answer
he
he thinks uh you know the
the the soviet bureaucrat or whatever
wants to hear
um but then also just the peer
calculation at that time
i think today we really with computing
technology
with artificial intelligence and various
algorithms
uh and cybernetics we really have that
ability to plan
a lot more uh than we did then so
you know one of the things that was one
of the things that the
chilean government was working on as
well was uh
the cybernetics with their um cybersin i
think they called it
this vast ability to compute and
calculate the various needs
um and resources of the society
in not a top-down model but more of a
distributed model
um you know uh different nodes
connecting and
talking to each other you see that today
like
certain people um on like the
accelerationist side or even
the marxist literary critic um
frederick jameson has talked about the
idea of
nationalizing walmart and amazon because
they basically
have most of that calculating
technology that would be required um
you know to do that kind of thing they
have the infrastructure there
it's just not there on the on the public
level serving
the public need uh then though to shift
from that
a little bit some of it is redefining
what is good and what the goals are
so you know
a lot of this work comes uh is kind of
directly related to the ideas of luxury
communism
um which just like acid communism is a
smashing together of words that you
wouldn't normally associate with each
other and kind of forces you to change
your definition of each of them
uh so producing public luxuries
uh like something that everyone has
you know public housing uh
infrastructures that are
absolutely beautiful and just for the
every person you know that's working
towards that would be vastly different
than
what we do now uh and trying to reduce
the working hours um trying to take away
toil from jobs uh from the labor that we
have to do
and making sure that labor is going
towards something
for the for everyone i think would
automatically kind of change
the way those markets are functioning
because like so
maybe um and i'm also not for
strong super predictions like i i don't
think our goal should be
necessarily to lay out an exact
blueprint by any means
even though i am also saying we should
be
inventing futures in a way so maybe in
the future
markets to an extent do exist
but not for things that are seen as
absolutely essential for life um
for you know social life and not just a
bare minimum life but an actual
beautiful life that everyone would enjoy
you know so
maybe markets become like a flea market
almost um you know you see that like
people want to trade they want to have
commerce they want to create you know
artisanal goods or
commodities on their own accord if
that's not the
the point of life or the point of
society
um then that's that's okay with me
personally like i don't care what those
people do and maybe that would
kind of drive some of those while the
vast uh
majority of stuff for everyone could be
produced in
some kind of way that doesn't rely on
markets like that but still takes in
all that information in a distributive
model where it's
not top down but people are working
together and across the board
they're probably a lot of this really
probably would rely on
computing technology which isn't
necessarily my
forte i read about it but i'm not a
programmer and i don't quite understand
it i have to ask my
uh tech friends to explain it to me
quick follow-up if i may um so i i'm
very
interested in this intersection that
you're describing between sort of like
emerging self-organizing organizational
um and knowledge structures uh which are
not top down
and using that sort of method or
perspective to reach the goal state
if you will of like fully automated
luxury space communism or whatever
and um and so i'm just wondering i'm not
super familiar with the thinkers in this
area do you have any people
uh you know blogs uh videos books that
you would recommend to explore this area
more uh
oh i hate um yes i
i think um so there's like the inventing
the future
uh by
nick i can never say his last name and i
always
mess it up but it starts with an s and
alex williams i think um
there's the uh the republic of walmart
book um i think repeater put out a
uh little collection called
futures and fictions which is really
good as well
kind of it has some of that in there
definitely deals with a lot of those
themes um other than that i would have
to get
i would have to look at a list more uh
sorry um but you know maybe even like
some some science fiction like uh like
kim stanley robinson
um something like that has elements of
that as well
you know he describes he's like in a lot
of his books uh these vast
moments of time and how the societies
gradually change into something else and
some of the societies he describes um
like i'm thinking about the society
in what is it 20 21
12 or 22 12 24 12 something like that
um but you know it sounds pretty pretty
amazing and pretty close to this it
seems post-scarcity
no one's doing uh work that they don't
want to do the work that is done
seems to be either self-motivated or for
the good of all
yet there does seem to be some kind of
uh
market forces like in smaller capacities
as well
you know thank you
awesome thanks evan um adam are you okay
to stay
15 minutes after the hour or do you have
to leave right at the hour
i can stay whenever as long as you want
cool because we got a bunch of great
questions i'd like to get to
uh most of them um harry you had a
follow-up question if you got to meet
yourself and
asked it yeah so it's along these same
lines and maybe you
you know already answered as much as you
would answer but my question following
up evan's question is
what's positive affects of um
capitalism or our current economic
system or even
our current social system would you like
to see brought forth and implemented in
any
new system that comes forth of you know
whatever
the future of tomorrow you would want to
look like is there anything you would
bring forward that is currently being
practiced
uh yes i'm sure there is you know
um i'm trying to think though that's an
interesting question um
i mean i think there's positive aspects
of capitalism
of course in the way that most marxists
would of it's uh
destroying of old forms of hierarchy and
whatnot but i think you're talking about
actual practices
um so
uh what is a an actual so maybe
impart the uh the ability to have
separation between
work and and and life you know um
that's maybe something that could be
explored to how to make that positive
uh you know because so before
in like a pre-capitalist society you
know your your life and your work
might be so completely tied up uh
that really those identities are hard to
parse out and in capitalism
definitely parse that out though today
as we're entering um more of a society
of control versus a society of
discipline uh and you know we're
all kind of have precarious job
employment we're
and connected through uh smart
technology
it seems like that erasure is happening
in a in a negative way um
yeah that's uh yeah i think that's all i
i could answer for that i'm sure there's
more though um i would just have to
think on
that exactly okay
yeah and i guess just another way of
phrasing my question would be is there a
baby that you don't want to throw out
with the bath water
um well i i mean you know
democracy as such even though i don't
think it's necessarily tied
to capitalism by any means um i mean
we're seeing that
with what you could argue with like
china uh where it
seems to be some kind of strange form of
authoritarian state capitalism to me
um but you know democracy and that idea
uh
liberty fraternity regardless
um equality like those
those are tied to liberalism um as such
so maybe not
capitalism but they've been associated
with it for a long time
and you know certainly
the right or someone who considers
capitalism a positive thing would
probably
consider those part of capitalism
especially if you're like
uh referring to uh during cold war era
for say like
um the authoritarian non-democratic
communist states versus the western
nice liberal democratic states um so i
think you do need to carry that on and
carry on a strong form of
anti-authoritarianism and uh
libertarianism in the
in the small l sense not the american
libertarian party
to carry those kind of attitudes from
capitalism
and you know maybe finally realize the
ability
uh capitalism promises this um
entrepreneurial spirit this meritocracy
uh and i think that's i would say i mean
that's pretty on its face been proven to
not be true
uh even as meritocracy was actually
coined as a word to make fun
you know it's a satirical word it's
because it's kind of uh saying yeah
there's a merit but it's
like in the meritocracy you know they're
inheriting their merit
um but maybe from there to
not carry those things on but finally
realize them
to move beyond them and pass them um
and like actually give that promise that
capitalism
claims it has
thank you awesome thanks harry uh
tarn you're up next
hey um so my question was um
could we have a redistributive
distributed model that looks outside
of the left right political binary um
and i was just thinking how fisher talks
about
um psychedelics being a root to helping
us imagine something new but
part of me thinks that this left right
binary is or is not necessarily
something new and
i wonder if we can kind of think about
the political spectrum rather than with
it
um yeah i guess you know
there i think it comes down to what you
mean by left and right
um and a lot of people have a lot of
different things i think
i i'm operating from
[Music]
a vague notion that the
the left is more prone to looking at
systemic
uh causes systemic to looking at
problems
as systemic rather than individual
um so and i think that is important to
look
look at so even in the stuff we're
talking about so if we're looking at
individual trauma
it's also important to connect it to the
social trauma
and i i wouldn't want to give that up
and i don't think
uh fisher would either because i think
it's also
not only about like this idea of the
acid left that we're working with
our goal isn't only to bring those
positive moments positive aspects of
psychedelic culture
to the left or broadly
political uh awareness in general but
also to bring elements
of like class consciousness into the
psychedelic
uh community so i do think for our
project at least it is important
to identify with the left uh rather than
in
a political stance because we do bring
class you know a class analysis to it
pretty
pretty strongly so and so to get back to
that like briefly uh
illustration of the systemic
looking at it systemically versus
individually um
so that difference between left and
right there i would say is
summed up in that phrase what is it the
uh anti-semitism
is the socialism of fools so
whereas like the class analysis would
look at this as a
large societal systemic structural issue
you know you could also frame those same
things pointing to a lot of the same
problems
as bad actors um disrupting the system
you know rather than the system itself
producing
certain behaviors certain outcomes
acting upon
individuals uh so i mean i hope that
answers that like
like i said i do i do think there's a
strong need to
look at both the individual and
the bigger you know the whole but
i think we're focusing definitely on
looking at those structural sides and
trying to allow the individual to
recognize you know parts of them that
are
uh predetermined the the the forces that
are shaping their unconscious
and their desires and producing um
all that what they're acting within
right uh i think sam's question uh is a
good fall to this sam
if you can unmute yourself and ask a
question
uh sure so yeah i i
appreciated what you were mentioning
about the rise of the alt-right and this
uh kind of tapping into these libidinal
energies that were being
uh loosed by them and how there is a lot
of energy in that but
i think that in recent years as things
have progressed given our current
media landscape um the incentives that
are driving it
it seems like a very similar um
tapping into libidinal energy is
happening on all corners of the
political spectrum
in ways that are kind of creating a lot
of fragmentation and decoherence
i'm curious given the current
landscape that we're navigating and what
you were talking about about using memes
and wanting to tap into that what a
strategic way of doing that would look
like to kind of
tap into those uh pervasive energies
and canalize them or direct them in a
way that would be
less destructive but also effective
given
given what we're dealing with these days
with with the media ecology
um interesting yeah i like that question
uh
so effective i don't know you know um
i wish i could answer that if i could
i'd you know we'd probably have a huge
reach if we just had that formula for
what is effective
um i think it's interesting because
we're seeing
younger and younger people enter the
online spaces and social media
uh there's a artist and
writer instagramer twitter youtuber
uh joshua citarella and
uh politics is memes
i believe or memes is politics i feel
stupid i can't
it's one of those um is this podcast and
you know he traces he did
he spends a lot of times in these hyper
fractionalized
communities and traces the development
and you see
the way you know he traces people how
they're shifting across and around and
diagonally and spiraling on the
political compasses
and they're reading you know left
communist theory at 14 and
neo-fascism at 13 and stuff like that
and they're reading like this
really intense stuff and becoming
radicalized so you're right it is there
it's like that
tapping into those libidinal energies is
all over
i worry though um
in some of the ways that a lot of it
is almost like
frying out people's uh nervous system in
a way though
and not you know uh not helpful not
healing
not uh like you were saying so how do we
yeah how do we actually direct that
i guess that's by the content that you
know you're choosing to engage with
um and there's always a give and take
there too like
the more you enter
the already existing meme world the more
that you're
taking from memes that are currently out
there uh you know you're kind of
sacrificing a part of whatever you're
trying to cohere
around you're giving yourself to that
but then also something to worry about
is social media memes
all of this often relies on hate uh
you know i can say from experience
our our memes that get the most
attention are ones that early on people
disagree with um so
and that's hard to avoid because like
part of me you know wants to be like
oh i hope someone gets mad at this like
you know they say oh you're not a true
communist or
you have no idea what the psychedelic
community is you know we get both of
those
and whenever that happens you know it's
like almost guaranteed that oh this
meme's gonna go far
because you know we're engaged in these
things and we're kind of in these
feedback dopamine feedback loops
and people are getting mad and sharing
it they're getting mad and arguing
so i guess within that space you know
you can also redirect it's not about
just about
posting the meme especially if you're
like a content creator and you're not
just sharing
uh memes but maybe it goes even if
you're just sharing other memes you come
across
it's trying to engage in that with the
people that
are talking to you you know the meme is
only
a gateway it's always going to be
hyperbolic it's always going to be
you know over the top and
maybe two on the nose uh overly
metaphorical
you know so like in our in our um
podcast we we of course touch on like
psychedelics like lsd and stuff like
that
but we also spend more time exploring
these ideas other ideas that aren't
strictly drug-related uh psychedelia
yet in memes it's so much easier to
connect these ideas with these like
symbolic or metaphorical things so you
know it's so much easier to go
into something hyperbolic like throwing
magic mushrooms
uh and a copy of das capitol on
a sandwich be like oh look it's an acid
communist breakfast
um you know that's gonna get people's
libidinal
energies uh caught in there and it's
gonna draw attention
but you risk a lot there and you know
you have to be
building a community within that and
engaging
both the love and the hate that anything
you're creating is getting
if you want to cohere it at all or you
can like just try to throw
wrenches in the system but i think that
is actually dangerous to
simply throw wrenches and uh you know
kind of hope that when it's falling
apart you can dodge the pieces
awesome uh so uh i'm gonna skip some
follow-up questions just so we can
squeeze in
um all the questions uh there's some
really good ones
uh kale can you uh unmute yourself and
go next
sure thing actually i feel like that was
a pretty good follow-up to that one just
because the idea of like um
i fall into that trap of sharing the
memes just because i'm trying to trigger
people you know
getting the angry comments is always uh
somewhat uh gratifying but i guess
that's the thing that i've kind of
witnessed with this
kind of leftist meme sharing is it
almost kind of starts to winnow itself
down into these weird micro groups
and i guess um that's just kind of my
question i kind of tried how do we make
sure that we don't just kind of explore
inward and get more and more insular
and try to actually use it as a form of
connection kind of thing
just because i feel like that kind of
that's the trap when i talk about my
hippie friends is kind of people miss
the point once they feel that connection
or whatever right then that kind of
almost elevates their own
importance rather than realizing oh we
all have this we all
kind of can work on this together kind
of thing i don't know
i'm terrible at verbalizing it but
no uh i mean i i get what you're saying
you're
absolutely right um that seems actually
that's like a big theme of these
questions which is
great because that's a question we have
as well
um you know i wish i had strong answers
for these
um but i think that's something that we
have to kind of come up with
together and that's what we're working
for so
moving beyond of course like like you
know we were definitely
guilty of it some of our memes or some
of the things we say
might be too heavily laced with irony or
satirism
but moving into like actual moments of
sincerity
um trying to connect with other people
and trying to show
a softness trying to show an
understanding of other
excuse me um of others you know and
i think you're right it kind of goes
like with you said your hippie friends
um
how an enlightening experience can
actually lead someone to become
more narcissistic uh in some ways and
yeah you have to fight against that and
you know that happens in political
movements too it's almost uh
the same way you see uh we can look at
the history of the left
and see that the history of the left in
the states um
and the constant fracturing of
uh little parties into micro sects that
become
basically cults you know there's some
kind of secular cult um
and you want to avoid doing that so i
think
sharing creating and sharing things that
really focus on a collective joy
um something i keep coming back to is
part of that you know like
so really trying to make those things
fun memes are one thing but
music uh music is a really easy thing to
collectively experience together and it
kind of
pulls you both out of like whatever time
that you're in and put you in something
there so if you can infuse
music with those kinds of intentions and
messages
that's something you know that's pretty
strong and you can make it fun
to listen to so that these things appeal
not just to people who are in the know
right like if you're only talking
to a small circle you're not doing
anything and you're not expanding
anything
um in order to expand any other circle
or group
you yourself have to expand and you have
to be able to
envision your you and
them you know the the us and them
together
collectively experiencing something as
good
um so yeah i guess that's my my answer
is really trying to focus on
actual collective joy and
and good times um without without saying
like you know it's like oh it's about
good vibes man because
that's not what i'm saying either but
like really actually um
the collective part i guess is important
there
yeah i like that serious serious play
um so let's end with a question from
kevin
about uh i like what you're saying about
the
tutorial thing kevin if you can ask that
one
yeah um so this kind of
taps into what you were just saying with
like building a collective joy
and like building a community um on your
youtube channel
you have a photoshop tutorial it was
like how to make a joe biden doomer meme
and i've never really seen like
political channels like explicitly
making tutorial videos like
you know i've never seen like a conjurer
points how to do a makeup video or
something like that
but um i'm wondering if
so like what the relationship is between
sort of educating people and making
these memes
and the ideology of say acid leftism
and like what you well first of all i
hope that you keep making the tutorials
because
your aesthetic is incredible and very
visually complex and
the sounds too so um yeah
that and i'm wondering like what if you
can sort of talk about
if you plan on doing that and what the
motivation and ideology surrounding that
would be
yeah absolutely thank you um i do have
to say though i think if
if natalie did a makeup tutorial video
it would break the internet i think like
i mean we need that you know i i need
her to show me how to contour because
you know the beard makes it hard uh
i really like doing well i have to say
mike has done
both of the uh the tutorial videos that
we have up but i'm actually making one
for this month um and i really like that
idea because it's important
you know he we're gonna try to explore a
whole bunch of
different uh
um digital creations so he did photoshop
i'm gonna do a phone one called mirror
lab
uh on our next one which is what i use
to make most of my digital art and memes
you know um
i do have it's like there's a free
version i have like the five dollar paid
version but you can do anything that i'm
going to show
on the free version and yeah the
the point is to engage and create
community to show people how easy some
of this stuff can be
to give them ideas um to kind of
democratize the process
itself um you know because you're
we you don't want if you're working in
this kind of project
you don't want to simply be giving
people content but you want to
you know be giving them the tools to
create content
you want um to create content that
furthers their own understanding
you know um i i truly believe no
not all of the stuff would fit into this
but i truly believe if you're
making a great image and you're
connecting a quote uh
with a relative juxtaposition of image
that that can connect something in your
mind you know
and help you understand that the
the concept or like the the um
topography of that concept
in a way much deeper than you would
just simply by reading it um and i don't
know maybe
maybe that's part of way my mind works i
often visualize stuff that i'm reading
or um in almost like collage collage
fashion
uh so yeah that i think that's a great
thing to do and you know that's why
we're doing
like the reading groups and stuff as
well it
it's like the same thing but focusing on
the other side of it
is trying to get people involved trying
to break it down
um in a really a democratic way
um between different
levels of education between different
classes age groups
creator and audience and merging those
together
so you know hopefully in the future our
goal is to be able to like
actually create books and stuff as well
uh through those kinds of processes
where we're
like making visual commentaries on
on essays uh you know that are made by
us and our community as a process
of both documentation and creation
through engaging
other things
thank you awesome so we're going to
land here adam any closing thoughts for
us
where we can find you what you're doing
now or what you're doing next
uh yeah absolutely so um
you can find me personally on instagram
at the at sign art a-r-t
dot o dot dirt d-i-r-t
um it's a name i make for most of my art
is
dirt son of earth you can find that on
facebook or youtube as well
uh you can find the acid left at the
acid left
on facebook youtube instagram
and we've actually just uploaded all of
our um
stuff to a podcast service finally
so you can find it on like stitcher and
most of the other
pod services um if it's not there now it
will be going up
um or soundcloud and yeah we're
we're about to put out a new video essay
on the youtube channel
about mark fisher and his uh infamous
hatred of students who smoke weed um
being a little hyperbolic there but uh
it's a
i would say maybe a misunderstood quote
from capitalist realism that's made the
meme world because of
uh how funny it sounds basically when
taken out of context
so yeah we're about to put out a new
video essay
and we we should
have another podcast coming out soon um
yeah that's it check them out it's it's
good stuff um
but all of our stuff is good and mike is
uh
mike is on he has his own youtube
channel as well which we used to
upload content to before we had the acid
left one
uh called theory wave nights so you can
find a lot of our
music and video projects on there as
well as some conversations with terry
tapp
and yeah yeah and that's it
beautiful uh so i'll make some closing
announcements in
a moment but adam thanks so much for
visiting us that's a really fun session
uh we'd love to have thank
um you i'll do some closing
announcements uh in about 45 minutes we
have greg henriquez uh who's doing um
he's part of a sense-making residence
here for the month of october and it's a
21st century vision of wisdom
so that should be really cool um laura
would you want to plug
um the metamodern deep dives that we
have here as well
yeah hey everyone uh so
mondays we've been having uh daniel
gertz uh one half of
ponzi freinox uh in the house to take us
on some meta-modern deep dives
through art spirituality sexuality and
faith i believe the next one
is sexuality so that'll be a fun one um
yeah so that's uh every monday this
month
uh 10 a.m eastern awesome
uh and tarn is in the room right now
turn you have a really cool event coming
up i was hoping
to put you on the spot a little bit i'm
hoping you could unmute yourself and
give it a little plug
unexpected hi um yeah on the 28th
uh i'm going to be doing an event with
my friend
ellie hayne on some of the problems with
the scents making scene
um imagining beyond the echo chamber and
yeah i'm going to create a discussion
around that
thank you tarn and i'm excited for that
uh uh turn alley or two kind of
insiders in the sense-making scene so
we're gonna it's kind of good to have
some
self-critique on this space um
and then tonight we have an event uh
with what is it uh
justin weinberg um at 8pm eastern time
uh
justin is the editor of the daily news
blog this is like the
philosophy blog that kind of if you want
to get plugged into the academic
philosophy where this is the blog you
follow and he's doing a session called
disagreeing well
which is very um you know resonant with
a lot of stuff we're talking here
uh so you can just check out the website
uh for that
and the website is the store.ca we have
a patreon and
uh our sub stack for a daily newsletter
so that being said
adam everyone thanks so much for coming
to the store